Jeremy Elliott

MSc - Computer Science Graduate

Graduating with economics and computer science degrees I can analyse and understand problems an organisation faces in a wider business context and utilize that information to engineer a clean and effective solution. Despite lacking commercial experience in tech, my masters has made me capable of operating and learning in unfamiliar environments.

≥ elliottjeremy26@gmail.com

07525701230

in linkedin.com/in/jeremy-p-elliott

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fund/Client Administrator Bank of New York Mellon

12/2018 - 09/2019

Manchester, UK

Responsibilities:

- Reconciled cash balances accurately between accounting & custody platforms.
- Investigated & analysed inaccuracies in cash transactions.
- Ensured strict internal deadlines were met in a high-pressure environment and provided timely responses to internal queries.
- Communicated and coordinated with other internal teams to ensure greater impacting 'breaks' were prioritised to be resolved.
- Supported the implementation of software to automate the investigation and resolution of repetitive breaks.

Summer Intern

Social Enterprise: JAVARA (Indonesia)

08/2016 - 09/2016

Jakarta, Indonesia

Responsibilities:

- Researched the state of Jakarta's E-commerce market and potential distribution channels.
- Developed a viable E-commerce strategy accounting for competitor's pricing & transportation costs.
- Presented my findings to the founder of the social enterprise.

EDUCATION

MSc Computer Science

Newcastle University

09/2019 - 08/2020

Achieved Distinction (79% Overall)

BA (Hons), Business Economics

Lancaster University

10/2015 - 06/2018

BA (Hons), Business and ManagementUniversity of Kent

09/2014 - 06/2015

International Baccalaureate Diploma: 33 points British International School Jakarta

08/2010 - 07/2014

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

University Ranking Visualisation App (06/2020 - 08/2020)

- Concept: Supporting university comparison through visualising university ranking data.
- Obtained and wrangled from university ranking data from 3 different providers.
- Housed Data in a mySQL database for efficient asycnhronous querying and easy maintenance.
- Ensured core features were implemented by using the agile development model.
- Implemented user interaction to visualisations allowing custom displays of data. This provided user specific insights to better support university comparison.
- Tech used: JavaScript / node.js / MySQL / HTML / CSS / D3.js / AWS

Android Carbon Footprint Tracker App (01/2020 - 06/2020)

- Concept: Tracking user carbon footprint and rewarding users for completing carbon footprint reducing activities.
- Collaborated in a group of 8, making use of Gantt charts to manage time and workload.
- Enforced version control using Git and established a remote repository and shared cloud storage using GitHub & Google drive, enabling members to contribute remotely.
- Designed and implemented front-end UI & backend logic for pages related to reusing personal items to avoid waste. (Tupperware).
- Tech used: Java / Android Studio / Firebase

VOLUNTEERING & HOBBIES

Korfball, Newcastle University - Player

Barnabus Shelter, Manchester - Volunteer Served hot breakfast and drinks to rough sleepers in Manchester

American football, Lancaster - Treasurer Established the club yearly budget and ensured club expenses were paid on time and in full